June 25, 2016

Ms. Laura Piluso, Human Resources Coordinator PowerStream Inc 161 Cityview Boulevard, Vaughan, ON Canada L4H0A9

Dear Ms. Piluso:

During my online orbis research, I was excited to see the current opening for Service Desk Analyst at PowerStream Inc. I feel my qualifications as an ASP.NET Programmer and your requirements are a good match. This is the reason that I am applying for this ASP.NET Programmer position with my resume and cover letter.

I have much experience to offer in this field, with bachelor degree in computer engineering and computer programming from Georgian college as well as six months as an Asp.Net Developer.

My abilities to create web application that meet client requirement, work as a team player, and meet deadlines combined with my attention to detail would contribute to my success in your company. I possess web programming skills, C# and VB programming skills, SQL Server, business writing skills. My outgoing and friendly nature allows me to interact well with other individuals at all levels.

I feel confident that, given the opportunity, I can make an immediate contribution to your corporation. The enclosed resume summarizes my background and experience and you can also contact my student development co-op/internship consultant, Rita Pittman for more information. Thank you for your consideration, I am available to discuss further prospects at your convenience.

Sincerely,

Riteshbhai Patel COPR Internship Student Georgian College

RITESHBHAI PATEL

10 Vanessa Dr Orillia, ON L3V 7Y8 Phone: (705) 500-4460 Email: ritz4460@gmail.com

JUNIOR WEB DEVELOPER

CARRER OBJECTIVE:

Aspire to find a position as Software Developer/Web Developer where I have opportunity to analyze and develop software that meet specific client needs and get platform to shows my academic knowledge and skills.

CARRER SUMMARY:

Over 1 year of IT experience in custom application analysis, design, developing and maintenance.

Experience of developing client server and web based application using various technologies such as ASP.NET with C#, VB.NET and SQL Server.

Good experience of writing complex query, store procedure and indexes.

Expertise in front-end technologies including HTML, CSS, JavaScript, JQuery, and Bootstrap.

Abilities to work with team members.

Extensive knowledge of Core Java.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE:

Programming Languages: Asp.Net, Java, C#, C, VB.NET and C++.

Databases: SQL Server, MySql.

Web Development: HTML/HTML5, CSS, JavaScript, AJAX, JQuery, Bootstrap and Web services. **Software:** MS Visual Studio, MS Office, Dreamweaver, Notepad++, MS Visio and FileZilla.

EDUCATION:

2015 - Present Georgian College, Barrie, ON

Computer Programmer – (Co-op) Diploma Program

Academic Dean's List – 90% average

2009-2013 Vishwakarma Government Engineering College, Ahmedabad, Gujarat, INDIA

Bachelors of computer engineering

GPA - 8.32/10.00

WORK EXPERIENCE

Sept. 2015 – Dec. 2015 Canom Inc., Orillia, ON (Co-op)

Web Developer – Maintaining website and create new pages as per company requirements. Handling Order and vendor summary and generate reports based on different criteria.

Nov. 2013 – Apr. 2014 Dupat Infotronicx Pvt. Ltd. (http://infotronicx.com/wp/), Ahmedabad, Gujarat, INDIA

Software Developer – Created windows / IIS based application, Developed Crystal reports as per client's requirement.

Working Platform: MS Visual Studio, AJAX, MS SQL, Server, MS Access, Windows XP, IIS and FTP.



July. 2012 – May. 2013 BISAG, Gandhinagar, Gujarat, INDIA (College Internship)

Software Developer – Created e-commerce website through sell images, videos and audios of different format and size. **Working Platform:** MS Visual Studio, AJAX, and MS SQL Server and C #.

PROJECT EXPERIENCE

Design and develop different projects/assignments in programming course at Georgian college and bachelor of computer engineering at GTU (Gujarat Technological University).

Technology used: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Angular JS, Mongo DB, Node, JAVA, C, C++, Asp.net with C#, PHP, MYSQL and MS SQL.

Development tools: Microsoft web Expression, FileZilla, Git hub, Azure, Visual Studio, Net Beans and SQL Server.

CERTIFICATE

Dec. 10 – May. 11 Dev Computers, Ahmedabad, INDIA **Diploma in Multilingual Computer Programming** – C-DAC, GIST **Course Content:** - C, C++, JAVA, HTML, CSS, JavaScript.

Grade: - A

REFERENCE

Available upon request.